



Mohammed Afzal Jani 9652768774/9247297868 Afzal.jani@gmail.com AVEPM5605N

# **Objective**

Overall 10 years of Experience in Windows Server Administration & Monitoring of Computer Hardware's and software including 2 years of experience in SCCM and 5 years in Azure Active directory services. Well organized job and change control, exhibiting project management disciplines. Self-motivated, fast learner, creative problem solver & challenging tasks.

### **Educational Qualification**

- ✓ B.Tech in Computer Science and Engineering from Syed Hashim College of Science and Technology, Affiliated to JNTU, Hyderabad, India.
- ✓ Intermediate from ST Mary's Centenary Junior College, Hyderabad, India.
- ✓ S.S.C from Amaravathi Grammar High School, Hyderabad, India.

## **Work Experience Summary**

Having 10+ Years of experience in Windows Active Directory.

- ✓ June 2023 to April 2024: Worked as a Senior IT Engineer in NTT DATA, Hyderabad, India on payroll of TeamLease Digital Private Limited.
- ✓ April 2022 to May 2023: Worked as a Senior Support Engineer in Microsoft Corporation, Hyderabad, India on payroll of Collabera Technologies Private Limited.
- ✓ March 2021 to October 2021: Worked as a Senior Software Engineer in Mindtree Limited, Hyderabad, India.
- ✓ June 2015 to August 2020: Worked as a Senior IT Administrator in Ducere Technologies Pvt Ltd, Hyderabad, India.
- ✓ November 2014 to June 2015: Worked as an IT Administrator in Highbrow Audio Visual Services Pvt Ltd, Hyderabad, India.

#### **Professional Certifications**

MCP - Microsoft Certified Professional in Windows 2012 server. (Candidate ID: SR9806251)

## Job Responsibilities in TeamLease Private Limited

# **Project: GSE - Microsoft Windows Premier SupportClient:**

#### NTT DATA

**Project Description:** The GSE Windows premier project provides support to all the premier customers globally related to Active Directory, User Experience, High Availability and maintaining the performance of all the windows operating system.

# Roles and responsibilities:

- Responsible for taking the owner ship of Ticket when received from Ticketing Tool SNOW and G-SNOW fixing the issue as per SLA.
- Working and resolving the issues of Active Directory Replication.
- ➤ Maintaining the Hybrid environment on-prem AD & Azure AD.
- Responsible for managing multiple subscription, Creating management groups, applying RBAC roles and Azure policies on management groups.
- Responsible for all Identity and access management implementation.
- > Responsible for implementation and modification of MFA as per requirement.
- > Performing Upgrade of Active Directory environment applying change management process.
- Creating and implementing the change tickets for major changes by following the client approval process.
- Maintaining and updating the security software's and other software's as per the client requirement.
- Resolving the High CPU and High Memory Issues by taking the required logs.
- Working on GPO issues such as GPO's are not updating on client Machines, after applying we are not seeing the expected results.
- Creating the GPO's as per customer requirement.
- Working on slow logon issues on Dc's and client Machines.
- Working on User profile issues and Account logout issues.
- For AD Related issues taking the required logs and analyzing the Group Policy logs.
- Providing the RCA for the issues to the customers as per the requirement.
- Maintaining the RCA and resolution records provided to the customer for future purpose.
- Working on Basic Microsoft Public Key Infrastructure issues.
- Performing administrative and operational task related to Certificate lifecycle Management.
- Generating renewing, installing and revoking different digital certificate by reaching the concern team.
- Responsible for creating and implementation of new project.
- Guiding the New team and providing complete training in understanding eachprocess.
- > Studying and getting updated on the latest technologies and patches released by Microsoft on regular basis.

# Job Responsibilities in Collabera Technologies Private Limited

**Project: Microsoft Windows Premier SupportClient:** 

#### **Microsoft Corporation**

**Project Description:** The Microsoft premier project provides support to all the premier customers globally related to Active Directory, User Experience, High Availability and maintaining the performance of all the windows operating system.

### Roles and responsibilities:

- Responsible for taking the owner ship of Ticket when received from service Deskand fixing the issue as per SLA.
- Working and resolving the issues of Active Directory Replication.
- Resolving the High CPU and High Memory Issues by taking the required logs.
- Working on GPO issues such as GPO's are not updating on client Machines, after applying we are not seeing the expected results.
- Creating the GPO's as per customer requirement.
- Working on slow logon issues on Dc's and client Machines.
- Working on User profile issues and Account logout issues.
- For AD Related issues taking the required logs and analyzing the Group Policy logs.
- Providing the RCA for the issues to the customers as per the requirement.
- ➤ Maintaining the RCA and resolution records provided to the customer for future purpose.
- Working on Basic Microsoft Public Key Infrastructure issues.
- Guiding the New team and providing complete training in understanding eachprocess.
- Studying and getting updated on the latest technologies and patches released by Microsoft on regular basis.

### Job Responsibilities in Mindtree Limited: India

#### **Project: Microsoft Windows Premier SupportClient:**

# **Microsoft Corporation**

**Project Description:** The Microsoft premier project provides support to all the premier customers globally related to Active Directory, User Experience, High Availability and maintaining the performance of all the windows operating system.

## Roles and responsibilities:

- Responsible for taking the owner ship of Ticket when received from service Deskand fixing the issue as per SLA.
- Fixing and troubleshooting BSOD Errors, No Boot Issues and Bug Check Issues.
- Analyzing the MSDT logs and other required logs.
- Responsible for backup and recovery of servers.
- Maintaining Security certificates for Domains, Subdomains and Multiple Domains.
- For AD Related issues taking the required logs and analyzing the Group Policy logs.
- Providing the RCA for the issues to the customers as per the requirement.
- Maintaining the RCA and resolution records provided to the customer for future purpose.
- > Guiding the New team and providing complete training in understanding eachprocess.
- > Studying and getting updated on the latest technologies and patches released by Microsoft on regular basis.

### **Responsibilities in Windows server Administration:**

- > AD users and object configurations & Group policy configuration for both DC andOU level
- Managing Domains, auditing user permissions across platforms
- Ensuring compliance with regulations and policies
- Private cloud in Hyper V cluster with shared SAN storage.
- Replication configuration between AD and Office 365 Azure AD for office365 emailcloud
- ➤ HP SAN Storage Configuration through HP 3PAR management console and assignthe LUNS and volumes.
- > DFSR, DHCP, DNS configuration and maintenance.
- > Implemented Active Directory Federation services ADFS for single-sign-on access.
- Implementing OS migration, Application migration and hardware up-gradation.

### Job Responsibilities in Ducere Technologies: India

- Installing and Deploying Windows Server 2008/2012, Active Directory, DHCP.
- Comfortably can Prepare Local Area Network and Manage the Computers in the Network.
- Configuring and Implementing RAIDs in Windows Server 2008/2012.
- Configuring and managing servers remotely using Integrated Lights Outtechnology.
- Create, change, and delete users in active directory account and email accounts asper requests.
- Installing File Server and assigning rights and permissions to the users.
- > Troubleshooting Connectivity issues, create users and configure other relatedissues.
- Perform daily backup operations, ensuring all required file system data aresuccessfully backed up to the appropriate media.
- ➤ Handling SCCM architecture, which includes 1 Primary Server, 6 Distribution Pointsand 3000 Clients.
- ➤ Monthly patch deployment: Perform monthly MS security patch deployment activity to keep the clients IT environment free from known vulnerabilities. Activity includes testing and deploying security patches as per the business requirement (Test, Pilot and Production phases). Maintaining the compliance for deployed security patches.
- Maintain updated knowledge of troubleshooting SCCM Client Installation issues using Client logs, troubleshooting SCCM client Packages/Application issues as well as setting up Packages/Applications and deploying to Client machine.

# Strengths

- ✓ Strong communication and interpersonal skills.
- ✓ Quick learner and willing to work under minimal supervision.
- Active Participant in knowledge sharing.

I look forward to hear from you and shall be happy to furnish any further information or references required